plumbcenter.co.uk 2019-03-29

# Policies | Wolseley

This Privacy Policy regulates the use by Wolseley UK Limited (“Wolseley UK”) of the information you provide when using the Wolseley website. It is to be read in conjunction with the terms and conditions of use of the site here". Wolseley UK is committed to the online privacy of all its users. This policy statement is designed to give a clear explanation of Wolseley UK’s data processing practices. Wolseley UK will be the data controller of any personal data that you submit when you register as a customer on the Wolseley website. Wolseley UK is registered with the Information Commissioner as a data controller under registration number Z6068171. 

Privacy

### INTRODUCTION

Wolseley UK Limited (“ **Wolseley** ”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you how we collect, use and look after your personal data. It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

See our [Privacy Controls ](https://wolseley.branchmarketinghub.co.uk/privacy-controls/)

### CONTROLLER

Wolseley UK Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as **”Wolseley”, “we”, “us” or “our”** in this privacy notice). We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy officer using the details set out below.

### CONTACT DETAILS

Our full details are: Wolseley UK Limited, 2 Kingmaker Court, Warwick Technology Park, Gallows Hill, Warwick, CV34 6DY. (Company Number 636445)   
Data Privacy Officer: [ dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk ](mailto:dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk?subject=Website%20Privacy%20policy)   
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([ www.ico.org.uk ](https://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance. 

### YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. If you notify us of any changes to your personal information we will correct, update or remove your data as speedily as possible. If you would like us to, correct, amend or update your information please e-mail us at [ dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk ](mailto:dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk?subject=Website%20Privacy%20policy). 

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU

We may collect, use store and transfer the following different kinds of personal data about you:

  * Name and contact details – this includes your name, title, billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers
  * Date of birth information
  * Payment and Financial information – this may include your bank account and/or payment card 
  * Purchase history – this includes details about products you have purchased from us.
  * Profile information – this includes your username and password for any systems or websites you have access to (for example eXtra)
  * Marketing information – this includes your interests, your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences
  * Survey responses and competition entries
  * Customer service history – this includes interactions with us over the phone, by email or letter, via the website or on social media
  * Information about your device and how you use our website and apps – this includes information you give us when you browse our websites or apps, including your internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, as well as how you use our websites and apps.

Unless we have told you otherwise in a specific privacy notice, we do not collect any special categories of personal data about you. This includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. 

### HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direction interactions:** you may give us your name and contact details and payment information when purchasing a product from us or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    * create an account with us;
    * register on our website;
    * purchase a product from us;
    * subscribe to our mailing lists or newsletters;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * take part in a competition, promotion or survey;
    * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions:** As you interact with our website and our apps, we may automatically collection information about your device and how you use our website and apps. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and similar technologies. For more information on cookies, please see our cookie policy.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources:** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources such as:
    * information about your device and how you use our websites and apps from analytics providers such Google based outside the EU
    * Name and contact details, payment information and purchase history from providers of technical, payment and delivery services.

### USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We (and our trusted partners acting on our behalf) use information held about you in the following ways:

  * where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you
  * where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests;
  * where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation;
  * for certain processing purposes, we may request your consent to authorise the processing. 

Our legitimate interests include:

  * Selling and supplying goods and services to our customers;
  * Protecting customers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfare;
  * Promoting, marketing and advertising our products and services;
  * Sending promotional communications;
  * Understanding our customers’ behaviour, activities, preferences and needs;
  * Improving existing products and services and developing new products and services;
  * Complying with our legal and regulatory obligations;
  * Preventing, investigating and detecting crime, fraud or anti-social behaviour and prosecuting offenders, including working with law enforcement agencies;
  * Handling customer contacts, queries, complaints or disputes;
  * Protecting Wolseley UK, its employees and customers, by taking appropriate legal action against third parties who have committed criminal acts or are in breach of legal obligations to Wolseley UK;
  * Effectively handling any legal claims or regulatory enforcement actions taken against Wolseley UK; and
  * Fulfilling our duties to our customers, colleagues, shareholders and other stakeholders.

### WHO WE SHARE YOUR DATA WITH

We will share your personal information with the following bodies. Please note that we will never sell or rent our customer data to other organisations for marketing purposes:

  * Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.
  * Selected third parties including:
    * business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;
    * advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others;
    * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site;
    * credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.
  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Wolseley or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * Governmental bodies, regulators, law enforcement agencies, courts/tribunals and insurers where we are required to do so: -
    * to comply with our legal obligations;
    * to exercise our legal rights (for example in court cases);
    * for the prevention, detection, investigation of crime or prosecution of offenders; and
    * for the protection of our employees and customers.
  * Other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * In order to make certain services available to you, we may need to share your personal data with some of our service partners. These include IT, delivery and marketing service providers.

### How long do we keep your data?

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data. Please contact us if you require further details.

### SECURITY

We’re committed to keeping your personal data secure and have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

To help us keep your personal information secure you should:

  * Keep your password and any account details secret;
  * Never distribute the URL’s for pages that you have looked at while logged in as a registered customer.

### INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

To deliver products and services to you, it is sometimes necessary for Wolseley to share your data outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It will be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. We will only do this if there are appropriate safeguards in place to make sure your personal data receives the same protection as when it is being processed inside the EEA. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

### INTERNET

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to us over the internet or to our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have legal rights relating to your personal data. You can get more information on each of the rights we’ve summarised below by taking a look at the glossary in the bottom section of this privacy notice:

  * The right to request access to your personal data.
  * The right to request correction of your personal data.
  * The right to request erasure of your personal data.
  * The right to object to processing of your personal data or to withdraw consent. **Remember, you can always stop direct marketing messages by clicking on an unsubscribe link in any of our emails or getting in touch via email, phone or post.**
  * The right to request restriction of processing your personal data.
  * The right to request a transfer of your personal data to another service provider.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above or if you have any questions or a complaint, please contact us at:  
Data Privacy Officer   
Wolseley UK Limited   
2 Kingmaker Court   
Warwick Technology Park   
Gallows Hill   
Warwick   
CV34 6DY   
E-mail: [ dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk ](mailto:dataprivacyofficer@wolseley.co.uk?subject=Website%20Privacy%20policy)

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. We will do our best to respond to legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### GLOSSARY

We recognise that some of the privacy law terminology can be a bit complicated, so we have set out below some further detail on some of the terms used in this policy:

### LAWFUL BASIS:

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract. For example, where we are sending you a product you have purchased from us or where you have entered a competition on our website, we will be processing your personal data on the basis that it is necessary for us to do so in order to perform a contract between us. 

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

###  YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS:

You have the right to:

  * Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
  * Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

Security

Wolseley UK will use its best endeavours to protect the information you provide. Access to your information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. The servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

To help us keep this information confidential you should:

  * Keep your password secret
  * Never distribute the URL’s for pages that you have looked at while logged in as a registered customer

### Who we share the information with, and your choices:

When you use this site and have not advised us to the contrary, you are agreeing that we may use your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy statement.

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

You agree that we have the right to share your personal information with:

  * Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.
  * Selected third parties including: 
    * business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;
    * advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we will provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in SW1). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience;
    * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site;
    * credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.

We will disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Wolseley UK or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use [INSERT AS LINK TO WEBSITE'S TERMS OF USE] [or terms and conditions of supply [INSERT AS LINK TO WEBSITE'S TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF SUPPLY OF GOODS AND/OR SERVICES – BOTH TRADE AND CONSUMER] and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Wolseley UK, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.]

WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

[The data that we collect from you will be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It will also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We] will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted [using SSL technology]. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at 

Data Protection Officer  
Wolseley UK Limited  
2 Kingmaker Court  
Warwick Technology Park  
Gallows Hill  
Warwick  
CV34 6DY  
E-mail: [webmaster@wolseley.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@wolseley.co.uk)

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

Cookies

What’s is a Cookie?

A cookie is a small text file stored on your computer or your mobile device when you visit certain web pages. A cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets web site operators know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. Cookies do not contain personally identifiable information such as your home address, telephone number or credit card details. By using our website, you are agreeing to our Privacy and Cookies Policies and consent to the use of cookies by us as described in these policies. 

What cookies do we use?

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below. We use the following terminology: 

  * **Session cookies** – only last for the duration of your browsing session on the website. Your web browser would normally delete these when you close the browser.
  * **Persistent cookies** – these last longer than the browser session e.g. if you log into a website and then return to the website some days later, the website knows who you are and displays a welcome message to you. Persistent cookies enable this to happen. 
  * **First party cookies** – these are set by us 
  * **Third party cookies** – you may notice some cookies that aren't related to us. If you go on to a web page that contains embedded content, for example from YouTube, you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

Cookie name | Description and purpose | Session / persistent | First / third party  
---|---|---|---  
Apache | Default Apache cookie set by the HTTP server | Session | First party  
JSESSIONID | Default Java/JSP cookie that is created/sent when session is created | Session |   
WC_ACTIVEPOINTER | This cookie contains the value of the store ID of the session. This value is used to select the store to execute the command, if one is not specified on the URL. | Session |   
WC_AUTHENTICATION_ID | WebSphere Commerce uses a secure authentication cookie to manage authentication data. An authentication cookie flows only over SSL, and has a timestamped signature for increased security. This cookie is used to authenticate the user over SSL-connections. | Session |   
WC_GENERIC_ACTIVITYDATA | This cookie only exists if it is a generic user (-1002) session. This cookie stores the session values such as storeid, langid, contracts, etc. | Session |   
WC_PERSISTENT | This cookie is used to persist user ID, language ID, and currency for each store ID visited in the session. Multiple sets of identifiers can exist if the user visits more than one store | Persistent |   
WC_SESSION_ESTABLISHED | This cookie is created on the first request processed by WebSphere Commerce runtime. For example, a non-cache request | Session |   
WC_USERACTIVITY_ID | This is a user session cookie that flows between the browser and server over both SSL or non-SSL connection. It is used for user identification over non-SSL connections. It contains user session values such as login timeout, session identifier, etc. | Session |   
__utma | Used by Google analytics. Stores each user's amount of visits, and the time of the first visit, the previous visit, and the current visit | Persistent |   
__utmb | Used by Google analytics. Are used to check approximately how long you stay on a site: when a visit starts, and approximately ends | Persistent |   
__utmc | Used by Google analytics. Are used to check approximately how long you stay on a site: when a visit starts, and approximately ends | Session |   
__utmt |  | Persistent |   
__utmz | Used by Google analytics. Stores where a visitor came from (search engine, search keyword, link) | Persistent |   
_ceg.s |  | Persistent |   
_ceg.u |  | Persistent |   
_ga |  | Persistent |   
_gat_UA-84875841-1 |  |  |   
_gat_UA-84875841-9 |  | Persistent |   
_gid |  | Persistent |   
_hjIncludedInSample |  | Session |   
cookiePolicyNotification |  | Persistent |   
mt.v |  | Persistent |   
  
Managing your cookies

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. You can delete cookies stored in your browser by using a function in your browser. Whilst this does not mean you won’t collect cookies in the future, it gives you freedom to delete your cookies after you have been online.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit

Please note that Wolseley is not responsible for the content of external websites.

Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Wolseley UK is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites and accordingly assumes no responsibility whatsoever in respect of such sites. Furthermore, Wolseley UK does not endorse any products and/or services featured on any third party site. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the site in question. 

Email, newsletters, opt out and unsubscribe

Users have the option to subscribe to various email services, which we offer. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option not to receive these types of communication.

Updating personal information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes we will correct, update or remove that user's personal data as speedily as possible. You may request details of the personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. This fee will not exceed £10. If you would like a copy of the information held on you or would like us to, correct, amend or update your information please e-mail us at [webmaster@wolseley.co.uk.](mailto:webmaster@wolseley.co.uk)
